https://mbdi.com/website-privacy-statement/

Schedule a Consultation
[page_title]
Mastering Business Development Inc. – Privacy Policy
1. Introduction
This privacy policy (Privacy Policy) sets out the ways in which Mastering Business Development Inc. (MBDi), registered in the North Carolina, USA may use your personal data.
In this Privacy Policy:
‘we’, ‘us’ or ‘our’ means MBDi
‘the site’ means the MBDi website you are visiting or engaging with; and
‘you’ and ‘your’ means you, the person engaging with us, registering for our events or services or visiting our site. By registering for one of our events, subscribing to our services, visiting our site or otherwise interacting with us, we will process your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
2. How you can contact us:
Address: Data Protection Officer, MBDi, 7422 Carmel Executive Park Drive, STE 202, Charlotte, NC 28226, United States
Email: Data Protection Officer
Information we may collect about you
Information you give us:
We collect any information you provide to us when you complete registration forms, or provide us with your details over the phone, for example when you register an account with us, register to attend one of our events or subscribe to our mailing list. This information might include your name, address, email address, phone number, credit card information and other information relevant to the event or service that you’re registering for.
Information we collect about you:
We will collect any information contained in any correspondence between you and us via contact forms on websites, and emails or telephone calls.  We collect information about you visiting our website and how you use it. This may include your IP address, geographical location, device information, browser type, referral source, length of visit, operating system, number of page views, which pages you viewed and similar information. This information may be collected by a third-party website analytics service provider on our behalf and/or may be collected using cookies. We also use cookies and pixels in our emails to track delivery and open rates, the results of which are stored against your email address and profile. For more information on cookies please refer to paragraph 6 below
Information we receive from third parties:
We may collect information about you from third parties that we work closely with for the purposes of delivering to you the services that you request from us. For example, we may engage third parties to assist us with our online event registration systems or payment systems; these entities will collect information directly from you on our behalf. We may engage third parties to operate event websites on our behalf; these entities will collect information directly from you about your visits to the website on our behalf.
4. How we use information about you
We may use your information for the following purposes, depending on the relationship we have with you. Prior to submitting your personal data to us, we will provide you more specific information where necessary about how we will use your data and link you to this privacy policy.
We use personal data to:
The purpose of this is:
The applicable legal basis:
Provide you with information that you have requested from us, in relation to events and publications we run, or other services we provide (for example online webinars and e-newsletters).
We will need to use your contact details to keep you updated about the products or services you have indicated you are interested in.
By specifically requesting information from us, you are consenting to us using your personal data for the purposes of communicating such information to you.
For general administration and organization of our events, for example to contact you with information about an event or conference that you’re attending.
We will need to use your details for planning and logistics, to invoice you, to provide you customer service in relation to the event, and general administration of your attendance at the event.
Where you have registered to attend an event, we need to use your personal data in this way to perform our contractual obligations to you. Where you are attending an event but do not have a contract with us (for example you received free tickets), it is our legitimate interest to use your personal data for general administration and logistics of the event.
To keep in contact with you about other similar events or services of ours that may be of interest to you, or for research purposes after an event you have attended.
To keep you up to date on similar events or services you have previously purchased from us in the past. To analyze the effectiveness of our products and offerings to you.
It is our legitimate interest to keep you up to date on similar events of ours you have attended our exhibited at in the past. Where we rely on legitimate interests in this way, we will always offer an opt out, and unsubscribe option on any
Analyze user traffic to measure use of our websites and improve their content.
We may use information such as your IP address for analytical purposes of our pages, this could also include improving the content of our websites and services.
We have identified web analytics as a legitimate interest of our business and allow us to better meet your needs as a customer.
To comply with or abide by legal obligations or requirements.
We may need to use or process your personal data to comply with some legal requirements, an example being health and safety or fire safety at an event.
Where we need to process your data for these reasons, the legal basis will be compliance with a legal obligation.
You can find out more information on the privacy notice provided at the time you submit your data to us or in your contract with us (if applicable).
5. Who we might share your data with
In certain circumstances we may share your personal information with:
Selected third parties that we work with, where necessary for the purposes of delivering to you services that you request from us. For example, when you register to attend an event that we host, we may need to share your information with third party sub-contractors or service providers. Where we use such third parties, we take reasonable, appropriate steps to ensure that the contractor effectively processes the personal data in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy and our internal policies relating to the protection of Personal Data.
Any other third parties where necessary to enable us to enforce our legal rights, or to protect the rights, property or safety of our employees or where such disclosure may be permitted or required by law.
6. Cookies
We use cookies to ensure that you get the most out of our site. Cookies are small text files which we store on the device you use to access the site. Cookies allow us to monitor your use of the software and simplify your use of the site. For example, a temporary cookie is also used to keep track of your “session”. Without that temporary cookie (which is not stored after you quit your browser) you would have to log on every time you access a new page.
If you do not wish for cookies to be installed on your device, you can change the settings on your browser or device to reject cookies. For more information about how to reject cookies using your internet browser settings please consult the “Help” section of your internet browser (or alternatively visit http://www.aboutcookies.org).
Please note that, if you do set your Internet browser to reject cookies, you may not be able to access all of the functions of our websites.
7. Third Party Content, Sites, and Contributions
Some of our websites may contain content and links to other websites or apps that are operated by third parties. We don’t control these third-party websites or apps (including whether they store cookies) and this Privacy Policy does not apply to them. Please consult the terms and conditions and Privacy Policy of the relevant third-party website or app to find out how that site/app collects and uses your information and to establish whether and for what purpose they use cookies.
8. How we look after your data and how long we keep it for
We use a variety of technological and operational security measures to protect your information against any unauthorized access to, unlawful use of, and modification and destruction of any personal data we store. We will retain your information for as long as is necessary to provide you with the services that you have requested from us, or for as long as the law otherwise permits.
Where you have not participated, attended or registered to attend or participate in one of our events, or otherwise engaged with us in five years, we will delete your data, unless we have an obligation to retain it for longer (for example for taxation purposes).
Transmission of information over the internet can be insecure, and although we employ measures to protect your information from unauthorized access we cannot always guarantee the security of information sent over the internet.
9. Where we store your information
Where you are interacting with MBDi, our servers are situated inside the USA and all the information that we collect about you will be stored on these servers. In certain circumstances your information may be processed outside of the EEA such as when we engage third parties based outside of the USA. This could also be for example where you have signed up to exhibit, sponsor or attend an event outside the EEA. In such circumstances, we will take all steps necessary to ensure that any of your information is adequately protected and processed in accordance with this Privacy Policy, and where necessary, we put in place relevant safeguards to ensure the safe processing of your data.
10. Your rights in relation to your Personal Data
You have the right to:
Request a copy of the personal data that we keep about you, by making a request in writing to the Data Protection Officer. Our Data Protection Officers details are provided on Page 1 of this policy.
Contact the Data Protection Officer if you are concerned that any of the information we hold on you is incorrect, to have that data corrected.
Contact the Data Protection Officer to ask us to stop processing your data or withdraw consent where we are relying on consent as the legal basis for any processing of your data.
Contact the Data Protection Officer to request that we delete your personal data.
11. Changes to this Privacy Policy
We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. Updated privacy policies will be updated on the relevant MBDi website or provided to you at your request.
12. California Online Privacy Protection Act
According to CalOPPA, we agree to the following:
Users can visit our site anonymously.
You will be notified of any Privacy Policy changes on our Privacy Policy Page
How Does Our Site Handle Do Not Track Signals?
We honor Do Not Track signals and Do Not Track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.
13. COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)
We do not market to children under the age of 13 years old.
14. CAN SPAM Act
To be in accordance with CANSPAM, we agree to the following:
Not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.
Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.
Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.
Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.
Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.
MBDi Corporate
5030 Hardison Road
Charlotte, NC 28226
Main:
704-553-0000
Quick Links
Whitepapers, Columns and Articles
Careers
About
e-Learning
Contact MBDi
MBDi Insights
In BD … Always Live Your Cover!
Be Careful of Putting Prospects On A Pedestal
Is Business Development Your Halfway House?
If It’s Not A Must-Win for You … It Probably Is For Someone Else.
STAY CONNECTED
© 2020 Mastering Business Development, Inc. | All Rights Reserved | Terms of Service | Privacy Statement
Contact Us
Thank you for your interest in MBDi. Please fill out the contact form below and one of our team members will be in touch with you shortly.
Send
0
In this White Paper you will learn:
The different psychological profiles of BD Majors verses BD Minors
Criteria to evaluate personnel for a BD role
Why behavioral psychology is a critical knowledge competency for success in Business Development
The four distinctive BD roles and how to understand, assess and coach those individuals critical to revenue growth
Your Information will never be shared with any third party.
SUBSCRIBE
×
In this White Paper you will learn:
The eight-element approach to turning around revenue growth
Critical components for a high performing BD organization
Is it possible to change the culture of a BD organization?
Your Information will never be shared with any third party.
SUBSCRIBE
×
In this White Paper you will learn:
What a new BD culture incorporates
Why BD culture change produces a greater return on investment than strategy
How external catalysts are critical to changing BD culture
Your Information will never be shared with any third party.
SUBSCRIBE
×
In this White Paper you will learn:
Why trust is important in developing business
Why a client engagement process mapped to a qualification/disqualification phase is necessary
The three early shaping environments impacting your revenue results
Your Information will never be shared with any third party.
SUBSCRIBE
×
In this White Paper you will learn:
What the true ROI is for training and development investments
How installing a purpose-driven client engagement process impacts pipeline quality
Why to fund education, coaching and professional development for effective customer engagement thinking and skills
Your Information will never be shared with any third party.
SUBSCRIBE
×
In this White Paper you will learn:
The missing link in most Business Development processes
What is HUMINT® and why it's a critical component in intelligence gathering
How credibility in BD is determined by the level and type of questions asked
Your Information will never be shared with any third party.
SUBSCRIBE
×
Issue Paper:
Hiring retired senior military personnel for Business Development positions is a common practice in the Government Contracting industry. No matter how rational the custom of having retired military personnel call on their former subordinates now running government agencies or departments may seem, this scenario actually produces three troubling contradictions, one each from the individual, the corporation and the marketplace.
Your Information will never be shared with any third party.
SUBSCRIBE
×
In this White Paper you will learn:
Key Indicators of Revenue Growth Stagnation or Contraction
Stovepipe to Strategic: Restructuring the Business Development Model
Steps for Implementation
Assess the Present State of a Business Development Organization
Your Information will never be shared with any third party.
SUBSCRIBE
×
In this White Paper you will learn:
Indications of Business Development model problems
Business Development Strategy, Planning and Capabilities
Opportunity Identification & Qualification vs. The Crystal Ball.
Business Development Professionals vs. Door-Openers and Butterfly Catchers
Your Information will never be shared with any third party.
SUBSCRIBE
×
Issue Paper:
Few positions have the success of an organization weighing upon them like those in Business Development.
Once the hiring decision is made, a substantial and long-term investment of time and finance is required to launch the individual to the point where they are building relationships, qualifying and shaping opportunities and building a pipeline.
Your Information will never be shared with any third party.
SUBSCRIBE
×
In this White Paper you will learn:
Do You Need a Special Ops Team of Super Hunters for Your Organization?
Should You Stand Up a BD Strike Team?
Characteristics of a BD Strike Team Leader
Stand Up and Deliver: The Strategic Advantage
Your Information will never be shared with any third party.
SUBSCRIBE
×
In this White Paper you will learn:
A proven Intel Gathering Strategy to fortify decision-making and drive revenue results
The difference between companies that make good “Pursuit/No Pursuit” decisions and those that don't.
The five stages of the Intelligence Cycle
Your Information will never be shared with any third party.
SUBSCRIBE
×
In this White Paper you will learn:
Lifting a page from the small company Business Development playbook can be a game-changing strategy in this transformed environment.
Game-Changing Structure Strategy
The Case for Professional Development
Your Information will never be shared with any third party.
SUBSCRIBE
×
Issue Paper:
Want to get inside your customer’s head and discover the real issues? Then go to the source and just ask!
Are you gathering Data or Source HUMINT ®
Your Information will never be shared with any third party.
SUBSCRIBE
×
Issue Paper:
Determining Barriers & Overcoming Obstacles to Growing Revenue in a Recessionary Economy
Moving the Needle in Tough Times
Your Information will never be shared with any third party.
SUBSCRIBE
×
In this White Paper you will learn:
Guidelines for leveraging products and services to international military/defense markets in Government Contracting.
Top Ten List for International Business Development Success in Government Contracting
Your Information will never be shared with any third party.
SUBSCRIBE
×
